she's a very dear friend of mine and i
so much and so
thrilled
that i could be here to see your
reduction
into the international hall of fame
[Applause]
thank
how you follow that right
um first and foremost i want to just say
um thank you
for being here
um i know you did not have to be here
this was your choice and i'm truly
honored to have you with
international hall of fame um
we all know that
mr ratner single-handedly supports
probably every individual and every
organization that is here tonight
he never says no he has been dedicated
to cleveland to this region to the state
he never starts thinking stops thinking
and i swear every time he speaks i
learned something new he just gave us
information
that is a teaching moment and so for
that i just want to say thank you and i
think we should give him a round of
applause
not only did he help us start louisville
cleveland it was his brainchild and most
of you don't know louisville cleveland
is here today because when mayor jackson
first became mayor
the the buzzwords out in the universe
was start an office of welcoming and
mayor jackson said i do not want to
start an open an office of welcoming
because when i'm gone and somebody
doesn't want an officer well for me how
will it live on and so we started global
cleveland um and with that his point was
that it should sustain and live beyond
cleveland city hall and so mr ratner
helped fund and help start the first
office of global cleveland he also
helped start and fund the center for
population dynamics at cleveland state
university so again these are things
that he believed in that he helped start
i want to also thank debbie and dan
hansen
and honor also their late mom
we would not be here tonight if it
wasn't for them
all things cleveland international they
volunteer and do
some of us support them this event we
support but a lot of the stuff they do
on their own and so for that we should
remember that that end of the year we
have an extra few bucks if we want to
give something to charity we should give
to them because they give to us all the
time for that i want to say thank you
i'd like to also thank
my council president langford who's also
my councilman who i'm going to say and
his favorite resident tonight councilman
polizzik is here there are a lot of
people that are here tonight that's in
this room that i have said i've had the
pleasure of working with serving with
serving
serving with you
i don't like to say
we work together as a team
you know we've done some great things i
had the pleasure of serving the city of
cleveland for 22 and a half years
22 and a half i started when i was two
22 and a half years and in that time i
think we've done some fantastic things
and we did everything right now
but one thing we did do
we opened the doors of city hall to the
international community when i said we
opened the doors how many of you are
ever called to say hey valerie can we
get a permit to sponsor something in the
rotunda and we didn't charge you for
that
we got an ambassador coming to town can
we get the
flag raised up on city hall
does the mayor have time to meet can we
get a literal welcome can we get a
proclamation welcome all of those things
that seem like they're minor they're not
minor they are important because they're
important music because they're
important to us
and so if i leave you with one thing i
leave you with this remember we are all
immigrants i'm african-american
i did the you know the dna test
i'm from all over the place allegedly
but we are all immigrants
and and remember that when we're
watching the national news
and we're hearing stories about
immigration and the policies and the
procedures don't turn a blind eye to
that pay attention to what's happening
in ukraine
and stand with our brothers and sisters
stand together get together
live together and love each other
because we are all that we have thank
you
[Music]